<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Orange Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Orange Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>nl</language>
    <copyright>© ACTA. All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHealth PPS Call 2026</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/orangehealth-pps-call-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/orangehealth-pps-call-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;De nieuwe ORANGEHealth PPS Call 2026 is uit: Kijk op &lt;a href=&#34;https://orangehealth.nl/orangehealth-ppp/&#34;&gt;https://orangehealth.nl/orangehealth-ppp/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positief advies voor ORANGEHealth-PPS 2026</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/update-oh-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/update-oh-ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Het ORANGEHealth-PPS programma heeft in 2025 de “Innovation Booster” call uitgevoerd, een voortgangsrapportage opgesteld,  en hierover een interviewvergadering gevoerd met Health-Holland. Op basis hiervan heeft Health-Holland een positief advies afgegeven voor de start van het komende programmajaar 2026, met de daarbij horende PPS-toelage van € 1,35 miljoen. Voor de uitvoering van het programma zal het ORANGEHealth-PPS programma medio januari een nieuwe call tekst publiceren getiteld “Passende, Persoonsgerichte, Effectieve &amp;amp; Doelmatige Zorg”. Alle bijbehorende aanvraagformulieren worden natuurlijk ook weer ter beschikbaar gesteld via onze website. Wij kijken met veel enthousiasme uit naar het nieuwe programmajaar en de verdere samenwerking.  Tot slot wensen wij iedereen fijne feestdagen en een healthy en inspirerend nieuwjaar!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHealth en ORANGEForce onderzoekersdag 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/oh-en-of-onderzoekersdag-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/oh-en-of-onderzoekersdag-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Op 8 december 2025 organiseerden ORANGEHealth en ORANGEForce opnieuw hun jaarlijkse onderzoekersdag, dit keer bij de afdeling Tandheelkunde van het Radboudumc in Nijmegen. Meer dan veertig onderzoekers namen deel. Tijdens het plenaire programma werden korte updates gegeven over de voortgang binnen de drie onderzoekslijnen. Vervolgens werd de blik op de toekomst gericht, met een bondige toelichting op het PPS-programma en mogelijke aanknopingspunten—daarbinnen én daarbuiten—voor toekomstige onderzoeksvoorstellen. Daarna gingen de onderzoekers uiteen in drie werkgroepen om nieuwe initiatieven verder vorm te geven. De dag werd afgesloten met een gezellige borrel. Al met al kijken we terug op een zeer geslaagde dag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHEALTH-PPS “Innovation Booster” projecten op Dutch Dental Science Days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/dds-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/dds-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Op donderdag 19 en vrijdag 20 Maart 2026 vinden de jaarlijkse Dutch Dental Science Days plaats, in hotel de Werelt in Lunteren. Op vrijdag 20 Maart zal het middagprogramma worden verzorgd door het ORANGEHealth-PPS programma. Tijdens deze middag zullen o.a. de nieuwe toegekende projecten vanuit de Innovation Booster ronde zich presenteren. Iedereen is hierbij van harte uitgenodigd ! Inschrijven gaat via:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://dds-days-2026.webnode.nl/&#34;&gt;https://dds-days-2026.webnode.nl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join ORANGEHealth PPP and realize your project!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/join-orangehealth-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/join-orangehealth-ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you have an innovative idea in the field of dental care that could use support, in collaboration with a private partner? Submit your grant application now. The Orange Health PPP program launches Innovation Booster 2025. This scheme offers financial support for collaborations with private partners. The pre-application procedure is simple, and we are happy to think along with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 2025, approximately 10 ORANGEHealth PPP projects will be awarded, each with a PPP contribution of €50-100k.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consortia applying must consist of at least 2 ORANGEHealth core partners (university and university of applied sciences) and a Dutch private party.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The duration of an Innovation Booster project is 12-24 months.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Online Q&amp;amp;A session on February 13 from 16:00-17:00, register at: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:lian.verschoor@hu.nl&#34;&gt;lian.verschoor@hu.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The deadline for the pre-proposal is April 16, 2025, 17:00, and for the full application is September 3, 2025, 17:00.&#xA;Do you have any questions or need advice? Contact us.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frank Walboomers &amp;amp; Katarina Jerkovic, Program Leaders ORANGEHealth&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter Orange Health 2024 december</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/newsletter-2024-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/newsletter-2024-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On December 9th, the annual ORANGEHealth Researchers’ Day took place, which attracted great interest from consortium members representing all seven knowledge institutes. After a brief update on the current state of affairs within the ORANGEHealth consortium by the new program leaders Frank Walboomers and Katarina Jerkovic, the remainder of the program was expertly moderated by the chair of the day, Egija Zaura.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme of the day was “matchmaking”. Knowledge institutions were given the opportunity to present new research ideas, focusing on the rationale (problem articulation), potential research questions/objectives, research methodology and design, possible partners, and funding opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter Orange Health 2024 juni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/newsletter-2024-juni/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/newsletter-2024-juni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, June 14, 2024, the second partner day of the ORANGEForce project took place. The day coincided with the Dutch Dental Science Days of all dental care training programs in the Netherlands and was well attended. In addition to the researchers, there were representatives from various partners such as Philips, KIMO, the professional associations KNMT and NVM, the Dutch Association for Gerodontology, NIVEL, Vitadent, the new partner Omnios, the elderly delegation from NUZO, and other dental care professionals. RIVM, VWS, and Health Holland also followed the latest developments of ORANGEForce with great interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farwell Willem Fokkema</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/farewell-willem-fokkema/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/farewell-willem-fokkema/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 6, 2024, Willem Fokkema retired as Program Leader of ORANGEHealth to enjoy his well-deserved retirement. Willem has been of immense importance as a pioneer of the public-private consortium ORANGEHealth, and has always effectively, connectively, and enthusiastically carried out our mission to implement the preventive model of dental care in general healthcare. We want to thank Willem for his tireless efforts and wish him all the best for the future. Happy sailing!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newletter 2023 december</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/newsletter-2023-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nl/posts/newsletter-2023-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2024, the ORANGEHealth team wishes you an inspiring and successful year. We would like to give you an update of everything that has been achieved by our researchers and partners in the first full year of our Kickstart project ORANGEFORCE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ORANGEFORCE project focuses specifically on oral care for older persons from a holistic approach. After all, an unhealthy mouth irrevocably leads to a reduction in overall health. Especially in the case of frail older people, in combination with other conditions and the use of medications, the focus on oral health can be weakened and lead to unnecessary reductions in quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
