<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Orange Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Orange Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© ACTA. All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEFORCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/orangeforce-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/orangeforce-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORANGEFORCE is the Kickstart project of the ORANGEHealth consortium that has been running for three years now. ORANGEFORCE (ORal ANd GEneral For OldeR People’s CarE) aims to ensure that elderly individuals are well-connected to the (oral) care system and remain so. We achieve this by developing guidelines that are not only useful in dental and oral care practices but also in professional care settings (care institutions, general practitioners). Besides initiating physical collaboration and consultation between oral care professionals and primary care, efforts are being made to make (patient) information accessible, allowing data to be used for research purposes. Finally, research on saliva and databases increasingly reveals the relationship between overall health and oral health, and work is being done on supportive diagnostic tools for oral care professionals and primary care to recognize underlying diseases as early as possible through the mouth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHealth PPP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/orangehealth-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/orangehealth-ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pre-proposal-round-2026-appropriate-personalised-effective--efficient-care&#34;&gt;Pre-Proposal round 2026 ‘Appropriate, Personalised, Effective &amp;amp; Efficient Care’&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you have an innovative idea in dentistry and oral care that could use support, in collaboration with a private partner? Then it is time to submit your grant application now. The ORANGEHealth PPP program is issuing the call for the &amp;ldquo;Appropriate, Person-Centered, Effective &amp;amp; Efficient Care&amp;rdquo; round here. This program offers financial support for collaborations with private partners. In 2026, approximately 7-8 ORANGEHealth PPP projects will be awarded, each with a PPP contribution of €100,000-250,000. Applicant consortia must consist of at least two members of the ORANGEHealth program group (university and university of applied sciences) and a Dutch private party. Of course, multiple other partners may also be involved. The project duration is 24-48 months. The deadline for the full application is September 2, 2026, at 5:00 PM (by invitation only).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-impact-of-saliva-collection-methods-on-measured-salivary-biomarker-levels&#34;&gt;The impact of saliva collection methods on measured salivary biomarker levels&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H Al Habobe, EB Haverkort, K Nazmi, AP Van Splunter, RHH Pieters, FJ Bikker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2023.117628&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2023.117628&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saliva diagnostics have become increasingly popular due to their non-invasive nature and patient-friendly collection process. Various collection methods are available, yet these are not always well standardized for either quantitative or qualitative analysis. In line, the objective of this study was to evaluate if measured levels of various biomarkers in the saliva of healthy individuals were affected by three distinct saliva collection methods: 1) unstimulated saliva, 2) chew stimulated saliva, and 3) oral rinse. Saliva samples from 30 healthy individuals were obtained by the three collection methods. Then, the levels of various salivary biomarkers such as proteins and ions were determined. It was found that levels of various biomarkers obtained from unstimulated saliva were comparable to those in chew stimulated saliva. The levels of potassium, sodium, and amylase activity differed significantly among the three collection methods. Levels of all biomarkers measured using the oral rinse method significantly differed from those obtained from unstimulated and chew-stimulated saliva. In conclusion, both unstimulated and chew-stimulated saliva provided comparable levels for a diverse group of biomarkers. However, the results obtained from the oral rinse method significantly differed from those of unstimulated and chew-stimulated saliva, due to the diluted nature of the saliva extract&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/partners/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-you-want-to-participate-in-orangehealth-please-contact&#34;&gt;Do you want to participate in ORANGEHealth? Please contact&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Frank Walboomers &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Frank.Walboomers@radboudumc.nl&#34;&gt;Frank.Walboomers@radboudumc.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jenny Cadée &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jenny.cadee@hu.nl&#34;&gt;jenny.cadee@hu.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHealth PPS Call 2026</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/orangehealth-pps-call-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/orangehealth-pps-call-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new ORANGEHealth PPS Call 2026 is out: please check &lt;a href=&#34;https://orangehealth.nl/orangehealth-ppp/&#34;&gt;https://orangehealth.nl/orangehealth-ppp/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positive recommendation for ORANGEHealth-PPS 2026</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/update-oh-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/update-oh-ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, the ORANGEHealth-PPS program carried out the “Innovation Booster” call, drew up a progress report, and held an interview meeting with Health-Holland about it. Based on this, Health-Holland issued a positive recommendation for the start of the coming program year 2026, with the associated PPS grant of €1.35 million. To implement the program, the ORANGEHealth-PPS program will publish a new call text in mid-January entitled “Appropriate, Person-Centered, Effective &amp;amp; Efficient Care.” All associated application forms will, of course, also be made available on our website. We look forward to the new program year and further collaboration with great enthusiasm.  Finally, we wish everyone happy holidays and a healthy and inspiring New Year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHealth and ORANGEForce research 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oh-en-of-onderzoekersdag-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oh-en-of-onderzoekersdag-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 8 December 2025, ORANGEHealth and ORANGEForce once again organised their annual Research Day, this time at the Dentistry Department of Radboudumc in Nijmegen. More than forty researchers took part. During the plenary programme, brief updates were given on the progress made within the three lines of research. The focus then shifted to the future, with a concise explanation of the PPP programme and possible starting points—both within and outside it—for future research proposals. The researchers then split into three working groups to further shape new initiatives. The day ended with a convivial drinks reception. All in all, we can look back on a very successful day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORANGEHEALTH-PPS “Innovation Booster” projects at Dutch Dental Science Days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dds-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dds-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, March 19, and Friday, March 20, 2026, the annual Dutch Dental Science Days will take place at Hotel De Werelt in Lunteren. On Friday, March 20, the afternoon program will be hosted by the ORANGEHealth-PPS initiative. During this session, the newly awarded projects from the Innovation Booster round will present themselves. Everyone is warmly invited to join! Registration is available via: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dds-days-2026.webnode.nl/&#34;&gt;https://dds-days-2026.webnode.nl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join ORANGEHealth PPP and realize your project!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/join-orangehealth-ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/join-orangehealth-ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you have an innovative idea in the field of dental care that could use support, in collaboration with a private partner? Submit your grant application now. The Orange Health PPP program launches Innovation Booster 2025. This scheme offers financial support for collaborations with private partners. The pre-application procedure is simple, and we are happy to think along with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 2025, approximately 10 ORANGEHealth PPP projects will be awarded, each with a PPP contribution of €50-100k.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consortia applying must consist of at least 2 ORANGEHealth core partners (university and university of applied sciences) and a Dutch private party.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The duration of an Innovation Booster project is 12-24 months.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Online Q&amp;amp;A session on February 13 from 16:00-17:00, register at: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:lian.verschoor@hu.nl&#34;&gt;lian.verschoor@hu.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The deadline for the pre-proposal is April 16, 2025, 17:00, and for the full application is September 3, 2025, 17:00.&#xA;Do you have any questions or need advice? Contact us.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frank Walboomers &amp;amp; Katarina Jerkovic, Program Leaders ORANGEHealth&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter Orange Health 2024 december</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/newsletter-2024-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/newsletter-2024-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On December 9th, the annual ORANGEHealth Researchers’ Day took place, which attracted great interest from consortium members representing all seven knowledge institutes. After a brief update on the current state of affairs within the ORANGEHealth consortium by the new program leaders Frank Walboomers and Katarina Jerkovic, the remainder of the program was expertly moderated by the chair of the day, Egija Zaura.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme of the day was “matchmaking”. Knowledge institutions were given the opportunity to present new research ideas, focusing on the rationale (problem articulation), potential research questions/objectives, research methodology and design, possible partners, and funding opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter Orange Health 2024 juni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/newsletter-2024-juni/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/newsletter-2024-juni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, June 14, 2024, the second partner day of the ORANGEForce project took place. The day coincided with the Dutch Dental Science Days of all dental care training programs in the Netherlands and was well attended. In addition to the researchers, there were representatives from various partners such as Philips, KIMO, the professional associations KNMT and NVM, the Dutch Association for Gerodontology, NIVEL, Vitadent, the new partner Omnios, the elderly delegation from NUZO, and other dental care professionals. RIVM, VWS, and Health Holland also followed the latest developments of ORANGEForce with great interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farwell Willem Fokkema</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/farewell-willem-fokkema/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/farewell-willem-fokkema/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 6, 2024, Willem Fokkema retired as Program Leader of ORANGEHealth to enjoy his well-deserved retirement. Willem has been of immense importance as a pioneer of the public-private consortium ORANGEHealth, and has always effectively, connectively, and enthusiastically carried out our mission to implement the preventive model of dental care in general healthcare. We want to thank Willem for his tireless efforts and wish him all the best for the future. Happy sailing!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newletter 2023 december</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/newsletter-2023-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/newsletter-2023-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2024, the ORANGEHealth team wishes you an inspiring and successful year. We would like to give you an update of everything that has been achieved by our researchers and partners in the first full year of our Kickstart project ORANGEFORCE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ORANGEFORCE project focuses specifically on oral care for older persons from a holistic approach. After all, an unhealthy mouth irrevocably leads to a reduction in overall health. Especially in the case of frail older people, in combination with other conditions and the use of medications, the focus on oral health can be weakened and lead to unnecessary reductions in quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cohort_globe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cohort_globe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table class=MsoTable15Plain1 border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=0&#xA; style=&#39;border-collapse:collapse;border:none&#39;&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Characteristic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.7pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-left:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;&#xA;  color:black&#39;&gt;Name of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=scxw202229923&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &lt;span class=eop&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.7pt;border-top:none;border-left:&#xA;  none;border-bottom:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;border-right:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=NL style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;Dutch: The&#xA;  Gezondheid en Levens Omstandigheden Bevolking Eindhoven en omstreken (GLOBE)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative approach for oral care for older persons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research line is concerned with the research into oral care for older persons in oral care practice, vulnerable elderly people who need oral care at home and the development of the practice guideline for interprofessional cooperation on oral care for elderly people living at home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our research has shown that the awareness and implementation of the guidelines and the KNMT Practice Guide for oral care for older persons still needs to be greatly improved in oral care practices. In the coming months, we will make a plan on how we are going to do that. All ideas are welcome.The UMCG research into oral health among elderly people with cognitive challenges who visit a memory clinic is going well. There are already many participants and the results are promising. The first findings from this study will be published during the consortium meeting in June 2024. ACTA’s study on oral care for older persons in the home setting will start soon. Among other things, (cost) effectiveness, impact on quality of life and the reasons why older people do or cannot receive oral care at home will be examined. Researchers from Amsterdam, Groningen, Nijmegen and Utrecht are developing a practice guideline for interprofessional oral care for vulnerable older people living at home. With input from literature research, semi-structured interviews with healthcare providers and focus groups with general practitioners (and POH), pharmacists, oral care providers, home care and GGD employees, a draft of this guideline for interprofessional oral care has been drawn up. Through various cycles of implementation, testing and adaptation in practice, the concept will be adjusted and further developed into an effective guideline for vulnerable older people living at home. After that, the guideline will be used to support interprofessional collaboration. This design research will take place in 5 regions in the Netherlands. The contacts with the caregivers, but also with older persons are already promising!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LASA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cohort_lasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cohort_lasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table class=MsoTable15Plain1 border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=0&#xA; style=&#39;border-collapse:collapse;border:none&#39;&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Characteristic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.7pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-left:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;&#xA;  color:black&#39;&gt;Name of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=scxw202229923&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &lt;span class=eop&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.7pt;border-top:none;border-left:&#xA;  none;border-bottom:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;border-right:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;The&#xA;  Longitudinal Aging study Amsterdam (LASA)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LifeLines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cohort_lifelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cohort_lifelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table class=MsoTable15Plain1 border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=0&#xA; style=&#39;border-collapse:collapse;border:none&#39;&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=247 valign=top style=&#39;width:185.25pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Characteristic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=328 valign=top style=&#39;width:246.25pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-left:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=247 valign=top style=&#39;width:185.25pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;&#xA;  color:black&#39;&gt;Name of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=scxw202229923&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &lt;span class=eop&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=328 valign=top style=&#39;width:246.25pt;border-top:none;border-left:&#xA;  none;border-bottom:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;border-right:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;LifeLines&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=247 valign=top style=&#39;width:185.25pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-GB style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-GB style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&#xA;  / aim of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=eop&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US&#xA;  style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring health in the mouth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This line of research is the fundamental research component of ORANGEFORCE and focuses on innovative methods to detect early signs of abnormal health in the mouth. In the longer term, this may lead to new diagnostics. This line of research consists of two parts:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saliva collection and oral detection&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We investigated different techniques for saliva; An unstimulated saliva sample of 2 minutes or a mouthwash sample (20-30 seconds) appear to be reliable for (bio)medical research. In these samples, both specific biomarkers and protein profiles can be measured. Clinical pilot studies show a specific and unique ‘fingerprint’ for periodontitis compared to healthy controls. For Sjögren’s disease, the salivary ion concentrations of sodium and chloride appear to be a reliable biomarker. This also provides starting points for faster treatment for other systemic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral Cohorts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oralcohort-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oralcohort-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;worldwide-there-a-cohort-studies-with-general-and-oral-health-data-available&#34;&gt;Worldwide there a cohort studies with general and oral health data available&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GLOBE&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LASA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lifelines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;RODAM&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Maastricht Study&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RODAM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cohort_rodam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cohort_rodam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table class=MsoTable15Plain1 border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=0&#xA; style=&#39;border-collapse:collapse;border:none&#39;&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Characteristic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.7pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-left:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;&#xA;  color:black&#39;&gt;Name of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=scxw202229923&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &lt;span class=eop&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.7pt;border-top:none;border-left:&#xA;  none;border-bottom:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;border-right:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;RODAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=288 valign=top style=&#39;width:215.8pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-GB style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-GB style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&#xA;  / aim of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=eop&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US&#xA;  style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Maastricht Study</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cohort_themaastrichtstudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cohort_themaastrichtstudy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table class=MsoTable15Plain1 border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=0&#xA; style=&#39;border-collapse:collapse;border:none&#39;&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=150 valign=top style=&#39;width:112.65pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Characteristic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=425 valign=top style=&#39;width:318.85pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-left:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=150 valign=top style=&#39;width:112.65pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;&#xA;  color:black&#39;&gt;Name of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=scxw202229923&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &lt;span class=eop&gt;&lt;b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=425 valign=top style=&#39;width:318.85pt;border-top:none;border-left:&#xA;  none;border-bottom:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;border-right:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  background:#F2F2F2;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif;color:black&#39;&gt;The&#xA;  Maastricht Study&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoNormal style=&#39;margin-bottom:0cm;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-US style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/td&gt;&#xA; &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA; &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;td width=150 valign=top style=&#39;width:112.65pt;border:solid #BFBFBF 1.0pt;&#xA;  border-top:none;padding:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p class=MsoListParagraph style=&#39;margin-top:0cm;margin-right:0cm;margin-bottom:&#xA;  0cm;margin-left:15.55pt;text-indent:-14.2pt;line-height:normal&#39;&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  lang=EN-GB style=&#39;font-size:8.0pt;font-family:Symbol&#39;&gt; &lt;span&#xA;  style=&#39;font:7.0pt &#34;Times New Roman&#34;&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&#xA;  class=normaltextrun&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-GB style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;Description&#xA;  / aim of the cohort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=eop&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span lang=EN-US&#xA;  style=&#39;font-family:&#34;Calibri&#34;,sans-serif&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking and connecting oral health data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wp2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This line of research focuses on large-scale data on oral health. Ultimately, the goal is to build an infrastructure that supports a learning care system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part 1 of the line deals with cohorts. This is where data is collected about the health of participants. Sometimes oral health is already a part of that data, or it can be added. The data is usually collected via questionnaires, i.e. reported by the participant himself. In the picture of the Netherlands you can see the cohorts that have already joined. We are currently looking at how the oral health data of these cohorts can be combined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
